JEREMIAH YATES

☑ jeremiahyates1992@gmail.com **③** jyates92.github.io/Responsive-Portfolio/ **⑤** 5098693033 **⑦** Seattle, Wa

SUMMARY

West Seattle resident living with my fiance and 120lb Bernese Mountain Dog, Opie. I've been building computers since I was 4 years old and have always had a passion for development starting with tweaking my Myspace pages PHP. I studied political science in college and ended up working in Construction Management building high rises in Seattle, but I wanted to challenge myself for more.

EDUCATION

Washington State University

BS Political Science

Sept. 2012 - June 2016

University of Washington

Cert. Full Stack Development 2020

Mar. 2020 - Sept. 2020

EMPLOYMENT

MRI Constructors, Carpenter/Project Engineer, Seattle, WA

Apr. 2017 - Feb. 2019, Apr. 2017 - Feb. 2019

Carpenter in the mud to project engineer working in a professional environment in the preparation, pre-planning and resource forecasting and quantification as well as other technical activities relating to the project on low rises and TI's in the Greater Seattle Area.

Powell Construction, Bellevue, WA

Feb. 2019 - Feb. 2020, Feb. 2019 - Feb. 2020

Working in a professional environment in the bidding, preparation, pre-planning and resource forecasting and quantification as well as other technical activities relating to the project on Tl's in high rises and large retail facilities.

Chinn Construction, Kirkland, WA

Working in a professional environment in the preparation, pre-planning and resource forecasting /quantification, as well as a myriad of other technical activities relating to the project on the old FX Mcrory's doing a large structural overhaul of a historic mid rise in Seattle.

SKILLS

WEB DEVELOPMENT:: JavaScript, HTML, CSS , Node.js, Git, SQL, NoSQL, MySQL, GitHub, CSS Frameworks, BootStrap, Templating, Big Data, Data Analytics, SEO, NPM Packages, Typescript

LEADERSHIP:: Project Management, Strategic Thinking, People Management, Resource Management, Communication, Conflict Resolution

PROJECTS

Watcher July 2020 - Current

A full stack web application that allows users to function as a community in reporting first response events and hazards in there area. This functions like an extremely local news source that can be viewed as a pin to any area in the world.

Weather Application Apr. 2020 - Current

This is a simple weather application that calls on an API to pull weather from anywhere in the united states and provide a range of information from the UV index to a five day forecast.

AWARDS

Distinction in the face of Adversity, Spokane Rotary